<Document>
  # Immernacht Station - Server Rulebook (MRP)

  Welcome to Immernacht Station! We are a Medium Roleplay (MRP) server dedicated to creating compelling, character-driven stories. To ensure a high-quality and immersive environment for everyone, please adhere to the following rules.

  Our goal is collaborative storytelling. Your actions should make sense for your character and contribute positively to the round's narrative.

  Join our community on Discord: https://discord.gg/XNtp65CKvY

  ---

  # Section 1: General Conduct

  These rules apply to all players at all times on the server and on our Discord.

  1.1 Be Respectful
  We do not tolerate harassment, hate speech, bigotry, or targeted discrimination of any kind. This includes, but is not limited to, racism, sexism, homophobia, transphobia, and ableism. Treat all players with respect, both in-character (IC) and out-of-character (OOC).

  1.2 No Griefing
  Griefing is the act of intentionally ruining the game for others for OOC reasons. This includes, but is not limited to:
  - Mass station destruction without a valid and escalating in-character reason.
  - Spamming, whether in-game or via communication channels.
  - Intentionally causing excessive lag or crashing the server.
  - Targeting a player repeatedly across multiple rounds (metagrudging).

  1.3 No Cheating or Exploiting
  The use of third-party programs, scripts, or exploiting bugs to gain an unfair advantage is strictly prohibited. If you discover a bug, please report it to the administration.

  1.4 Character and Account Responsibility
  You are responsible for your account and the characters you play. "My friend was playing on my account" is not a valid excuse for rule-breaking.

  1.5 Advertising
  Do not advertise other servers or communities without explicit permission from the server administration.

  1.6 English in Public Channels
  Please use English in all public OOC channels and in-game OOC chat to ensure clear communication for all players and moderators.

  ---

  # Section 2: Roleplaying and In-Character Conduct (MRP Standards)

  2.1 Character Consistency
  You are expected to act in a way that is consistent with your character's role, motivations, and the established situation. Your character should feel like a person, not just a player completing objectives.
  - Valid Roleplaying is Required: Performing your job and reacting realistically to events is the expected minimum. Actions that make no in-character sense (e.g., a scientist randomly trying to break into the armory "for fun") are not permitted.
  - No Powergaming / Min-Maxing: You must not abuse game mechanics to act in a way that is contrary to believable roleplay. Your character does not have perfect knowledge of all game systems. For example, you should not perform complex surgery in seconds without any roleplayed effort or tool preparation.

  2.2 Strict IC vs. OOC Separation (No Metagaming)
  Using out-of-character information to influence in-character actions is strictly forbidden and will be enforced.
  - Information from Discord, streams, wikis, or previous rounds must not be used by your character.
  - Suspicions about antagonists must be based on evidence discovered during the current round. You cannot know someone is a Traitor just because they are acting slightly suspicious.
  - Use the correct communication channels (IC for character speech, OOC/LOOC for out-of-character chat).

  2.3 Escalation and Conflict
  Conflict is part of the story, but it must escalate believably. Do not immediately jump to violence or extreme measures for minor issues.
  - Provide a reason: Before attacking someone, there must be a clear in-character reason and some form of interaction. Randomly attacking crewmates is considered griefing.
  - Security and Command: Are expected to follow proper procedure and use proportional force. Unjustified arrests or executions are a serious breach of roleplay standards.

  2.4 "Memeing" and Low-RP Behavior
  While humor is welcome, behavior that breaks immersion or disrupts the round is not. Constant "memeing," nonsensical actions, or naming your character after a meme is considered low-RP and is not appropriate for this server.

  2.5 New Player Friendliness
  We welcome players new to MRP. Be patient and willing to help others learn. However, all players, new and old, are expected to adhere to the MRP standard. "I'm new" is a reason for us to help you, not an excuse to break rules.

  ---

  # Section 3: Gameplay and Antagonist Rules

  3.1 Antagonist Conduct
  Antagonists are catalysts for the story. Your actions should be clever, create engaging scenarios, and be focused on your objectives.
  - No "Murder-boning": Killing indiscriminately without reason is not permitted. Your goal should be to create engaging and challenging scenarios, not simply to eliminate the crew as quickly as possible.
  - Antagonists are still expected to adhere to all server rules regarding OOC conduct and harassment.

  3.2 Security and Command Roles
  Members of the Security team and Command staff are held to a high standard of roleplay. You are expected to act professionally, follow station procedure, and respect Space Law. Abuse of power is a serious offense.

  3.3 End of Round (EOR) Grief
  Do not engage in mass destruction or killing simply because the shuttle has been called. Continue to roleplay your character until the round officially ends.

  ---

  # Section 4: Administration and Rule Enforcement

  4.1 Admin Interaction
  - Admins are here to help. If you have an issue or a question, use the "ahelp" command in-game.
  - Do not argue with an admin's decision in-game. If you disagree with a ruling, please open a ticket on our Discord to discuss it calmly and privately.
  - Lying to or intentionally misleading an admin will result in a more severe punishment.

  4.2 Reporting a Player
  When reporting a player, please provide as much information as possible, including the round ID, the player's character name, and a clear description of the incident. Logs will be checked, but context is crucial.

  4.3 Consequences of Rule-Breaking
  Breaking these rules may result in a warning, a kick from the server, a temporary ban, or a permanent ban, depending on the severity and frequency of the offense.

  ---

  This rulebook is a living document and may be updated. It is your responsibility to stay informed of the current rules. By playing on Immernacht Station, you agree to abide by this rulebook.

  Last Updated: September 24, 2025
</Document>
