<Document>
  # Welcome to Immernacht Station!

  To ensure a fun and engaging environment for everyone, we ask that you adhere to the following rules. These are designed to provide a solid foundation for immersive and exciting rounds of Space Station 14.

  Our primary goal is to foster a community that enjoys detailed roleplay and emergent storytelling. When in doubt, use common sense and respect your fellow players.

  Join our community on Discord: https://discord.gg/XNtp65CKvY

  ---

  # Section 1: General Conduct

  These rules apply to all players at all times on the server and on our Discord.

  1.1 Be Respectful
  We do not tolerate harassment, hate speech, bigotry, or targeted discrimination of any kind. This includes, but is not limited to, racism, sexism, homophobia, transphobia, and ableism. Treat all players with respect, both in-character (IC) and out-of-character (OOC).

  1.2 No Griefing
  Griefing is the act of intentionally ruining the game for others. This includes, but is not limited to:
  - Destroying the station without a valid in-character reason.
  - Spamming, whether in-game or via communication channels.
  - Intentionally causing excessive lag or crashing the server.
  - Targeting a player repeatedly across multiple rounds (metagrudging).

  1.3 No Cheating or Exploiting
  The use of third-party programs, scripts, or exploiting bugs to gain an unfair advantage is strictly prohibited. If you discover a bug, please report it to the administration.

  1.4 Character and Account Responsibility
  You are responsible for your account and the characters you play. "My friend was playing on my account" is not a valid excuse for rule-breaking.

  1.5 Advertising
  Do not advertise other servers or communities without explicit permission from the server administration.

  1.6 English in Public Channels
  Please use English in all public OOC channels and in-game OOC chat to ensure clear communication for all players and moderators.

  ---

  # Section 2: Roleplaying and In-Character Conduct

  2.1 Roleplay (RP) Standards
  Immernacht Station is a roleplaying server. You are expected to play your chosen role to a reasonable extent. While we don't enforce strict, heavy RP, your actions should be consistent with your character's job and the situation.
  - Low Roleplay (LRP) is the minimum expected. This means you should have a basic understanding of your role and perform its duties.
  - "Memeing" or "shiptoasting" should not disrupt the round for others. Keep it contained and understand when it's appropriate.

  2.2 In-Character vs. Out-of-Character (IC vs. OOC)
  - Do not use information gained out-of-character (e.g., from Discord, streams, or previous rounds) to influence your in-character actions. This is known as metagaming and is strictly forbidden.
  - Use the appropriate chat channels. LOOC is for Local OOC, OOC is for global out-of-character discussion.

  2.3 New Player Friendliness
  We are a community that welcomes new players. Be patient and willing to help others learn the game. Intentionally misleading or preying on new players is discouraged.

  2.4 Escalation
  Violence and conflict should escalate naturally. Do not immediately resort to extreme violence for minor disputes. Security personnel are expected to follow standard operating procedures and use appropriate force.

  2.5 Self-Antagging / Self-Harm
  You may not act as an antagonist or cause significant self-harm without being assigned an antagonist role. This includes randomly attacking crew, sabotaging critical systems, or releasing a deadly virus "for fun."

  ---

  # Section 3: Gameplay and Antagonist Rules

  3.1 Antagonist Conduct
  If you are an antagonist (e.g., Traitor, Changeling), your actions should be in furtherance of your objectives. "Murderboning" (killing indiscriminately) is not permitted unless it aligns with your specific antagonist role and objectives.

  3.2 Security and Command Roles
  Members of the Security team and Command staff are held to a higher standard of roleplay. You are expected to act professionally. Abuse of power without a valid and compelling roleplay reason is not allowed.

  3.3 End of Round (EOR) Grief
  Do not engage in mass destruction or killing simply because the shuttle has been called. The round is not over until the shuttle docks at CentComm.

  ---

  # Section 4: Administration and Rule Enforcement

  4.1 Admin Interaction
  - Admins are here to help. If you have an issue or a question, use the "ahelp" command in-game.
  - Do not argue with an admin's decision in-game. If you disagree with a ruling, please open a ticket on our Discord to discuss it calmly and privately.
  - Lying to or intentionally misleading an admin will result in a more severe punishment.

  4.2 Reporting a Player
  When reporting a player, please provide as much information as possible, including the round ID, the player's character name, and a clear description of the incident.

  4.3 Consequences of Rule-Breaking
  Breaking these rules may result in a warning, a kick from the server, a temporary ban, or a permanent ban, depending on the severity and frequency of the offense.

  ---

  This rulebook is a living document and may be updated. It is your responsibility to stay informed of the current rules. By playing on Immernacht Station, you agree to abide by this rulebook.

  Last Updated: September 22, 2025
</Document>
